欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
10年前
21D 我现在在木兰路的安全屋
21- David. I'm at the safe house on Magnolia.
有警员受伤
Officer down.
枪伤 已无脉搏
GSW, no pulse.
请立刻派遣后援
I need immediate backup.
嫌犯可能还在屋中
Suspect may still be inside.
21D 目击者已死
21- David. Our witness is deceased.
遭到割喉 没有脉搏 重复一次
Throat slashed, no pulse. I repeat.
丽塔·马丁内斯被杀了
Rita Martinez was killed.
没有发现她的女儿
No sign of her daughter.
皮娅 你在里面吗
Pia, are you in there?
救救我
Help me!
听我说 你得打开门
Listen to me. I need you to open the door.
我得救你出去
I got to get you out of here.
皮娅 趴下
Pia, get on the ground!
救命
PIA: Help me!
拜托
Please!
皮娅
Pia!
没事的 没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
我来了 过来
Hey, I got you. Come here.
有我呢
I got you.
但我妈
But my mom.
韦尔杜戈杀了我妈
Verdugo killed my mom.
他也要杀了我的
He's gonna kill me, too.
不 不 那不可能
No. No, that's not gonna happen.
我们会抓到他的 皮娅
We'll get him, Pia.
我保证 我会抓到他的
I promise you I will catch him.
我会不眠不休 直到抓住他
I won't sleep until I do.
现在
PRESENT DAY
好 指挥官 听着不错
Okay, Commander, sounds good.
到时候见了
I'll see you then.
抱歉啊 尼歇尔
Oh, hey, I'm sorry, Nichelle.
好几个礼拜了 孩子终于
Baby's finally sleeping through the night
能够睡上一整夜了
for the first time in weeks
结果你的蠢丈夫凌晨四点把你吵醒了
and your knucklehead husband's waking you up at 4: 00 a. m.
-我的错  -没事
My bad. It's okay.
希克斯指挥官怎么这个点找你
What did Commander Hicks want at this hour?
你还记得我跟你说的那个
Do you remember that fugitive I told you about
几周前在墨西哥被抓的那个逃犯吗
who was picked up in Mexico a few weeks back?
很多年前
The one who killed
杀了那个年轻妈妈的吗
that young mother all those years ago?
加斯·韦尔杜戈
Gaz Verdugo.
墨西哥政府刚刚答应把他引渡回洛杉矶
Mexican officials just agreed to extradite him
接受那起谋杀案的审判
back to LA. to get him tried for her murder.
所以希克斯要我们出几个人
So Hicks is flying a couple of us
去墨西哥城押送他回国
out to Mexico City to escort him back to the States.
你联系她女儿了吗
Have you reached her daughter yet?
没 还没有
No. No, not yet.
自从韦尔杜戈被抓之后
I've been leaving her messages
我就一直在给她留言
ever since Verdugo got picked up.
你们上一次聊是什么时候了
When's the last time you two spoke?
有几年了
It's been a few years.
据我所知 她搬去了迈阿密
Last I heard, Pia moved out to Miami.
我一直在努力跟她保持联系 但
I've been trying to keep in touch, but
别太苛责自己 宝贝
Don't be so hard on yourself, babe.
过去几年你经历了很多事情
You've had a lot going on the past couple of years.
有了个孩子
A baby.
还有了个老婆
Now a wife. Mm.
所以希克斯有说这次引渡是什么时候吗
So how soon did Hicks say this extradition's happening?
给我们定了今早晚些时候洛杉矶国际机场出发的航班
He booked us all on a flight out of LAX later this morning.
你有时间打包行李吗
Do you even have time to pack?
女人
Woman.
我有的可不止打包的时间
I got time for more than that.
好啊
AII right.
墨西哥城
谢谢
POWELL: Gracias
根据刚才司机笑我的样子
Judging by the way our driver just laughed at me,
我的小费要么给太少了 要么给太多了
I either tipped him way too little or way too much.
我们也就在这儿待24时
Well, we're here 24 hours,
你还是把津贴用用完吧
so you may as well burn through that stipend
没必要小气
There's no point in being stingy.
别太自在了 帕维尔
Don't get too comfortable, Powell.
我们马上就走了
We'll be gone before we know it.
洪多一直在给谁打电话啊
Who does Hondo keep trying to call?
皮娅·马丁内斯
Pia Martinez.
被害人的女儿
Victim's daughter.
自从墨西哥联邦警察抓住韦尔杜戈之后
Hondo's been attempting to get in touch with her
他就一直在想办法联系她
ever since the Federales put Verdugo in custody.
我在飞机上看了案卷
I read the case file on the plane.
整件事都太可怕了
The whole thing is horrible.
在洛杉矶警局保护下的线人
An informant under LAPD protection
就那样被残杀
getting slaughtered like that?
我能理解为什么洪多10年了都放不下这案子
I can understand why it's stuck with Hondo the past ten years.
你可能不知道的是
What you may not know is that
是洪多说服了皮娅的妈妈
Hondo is the one who helped convince Pia's mom
成为控方证人 指证她的男朋友
to turn state's witness against her boyfriend.
当时韦尔杜戈是
Verdugo was a power player
洛杉矶萨尔瓦多黑帮的重要人物
in the Salvadoran mob in L. A. at the time.
我们努力不让洪多的名字泄露
We tried to keep Hondo s name from getting out,
但现在都结束了
but that's over now.
终于抓到韦尔杜戈了
Verdugo's finally in custody.
应该能让洪多安心一些了
That should give Hondo some peace of mind.
是啊 应该
Yeah. It should.
你肯定就是
You must be
包蒂斯塔警官了
Officer Bautista.
叫我加布里埃尔就行
Call me Gabriel.
我想感谢你
I want to thank you
这么短时间内
for handling everything
就安排好了一切 加布里埃尔
on such short notice, Gabriel.
我很乐意
My pleasure.
好吧 其实不是
Actually, no, I lie.
应付贵宾是我工作的一部分
Dealing with VIPs is part of my job.
贵宾吗
VIPs, huh?
我从来没想过自己会是贵宾
I've never considered myself a VIP.
你呢 指挥官
How about you, Commander?
我一直都知道自己很重要 但现在
I always knew I was important, but it's nice
终于得到承认了 不错
to finally get the recognition.
我知道你们不会在墨西哥城待太久
Well, I know you won't be in Mexico City
但我想问一下
for too long, but I wanted to ask
三位今晚晚餐有安排了吗
if you three had dinner plans for tonight.
我们想在明天大日子之前
Well, we were hoping to get some
好好休息一下
shut- eye before the big day tomorrow.
要是我说 我和我的同事们
What if I said my colleagues and I have reservations
已经约好了城里最好的餐厅呢
at the finest restaurant in town?
我们请客
Our treat.
警察怎么会错过免费晚餐呢
Never knew a cop to give up a free dinner.
-我就当你们是答应了  -是的
II take that as a yes. It's a yes.
在接到匿名消息之后
After the anonymous tip came in,
我手下的警官立刻就采取了行动
my officers acted immediately.
我们成功抓住了韦尔杜戈 在
We were able to pick up Verdugo in...
burdel用英语怎么说
How do you say"burdel"?
就是妓院
Uh, a brothel. Oh.
是的 在城市另一边的一个妓院里
Yes. A brothel across town.
我们发现韦尔杜戈经常性地
Apparently, Verdugo came here from El Salvador
从萨尔瓦多过来
with some regularity.
你之前说 你就是附近出身的吗
You said you're from nearby?
就在城外
Just outside the city.
我家在那儿开了家面包房
My family, we owned a bakery there.
三代人一起做事
Three generations working together.
但在8年的地震里被毁了
But it was destroyed in the earthquake in 85.
你还住在那儿吗
Do you still live there?
是的 跟我奶奶一起
Yes With my abuela.
她做的炸面团还是最好吃的
She still makes the best buiiuelos.
就跟甜甜圈差不多
It's like a doughnut.
你知道美国人有多喜欢
You know how Americans love
甜甜圈
doughnuts.
你们走那么快 真是太可惜了
It's a shame you're leaving so soon.
我想问你一下 警长
HICKS: Let me ask you, Captain.
你们知道韦尔杜戈来墨西哥城
Any idea what Verdugo was doing in Mexico City
-最初的目的是什么吗  -不知道
in the first place? No.
他被捕之后没有多说什么
He hasn't said much since he's been in custody.
或许你们回美国之后能有发现吧
Maybe you'll have more luck with him in America.
说实话 我根本不在乎
Frankly, I don't give a damn
韦尔杜戈有什么要说的
what Verdugo has to say.
只是能抓住他 我算是松了一囗气了
I'm just relieved he's behind bars. Mm.
都是多亏了你们
Thanks to you guys.
恭喜
Congratulations.
敬所有人
To all of you.
没错
HICKS: Yeah, hear, hear.
干杯
Cheers to that.
Cheers.
谢谢你
POWELL: Thank you,
韦尔杜戈的引渡 关注度比我想的要高啊
Verdugo's extradition's bigger news than Ithought.
他在萨尔瓦多地下巢穴
Well, he's run a Mafia operation from an underground lair
经营黑帮几十年了
in El Salvador for decades.
大家都想看看
People want eyes on him.
那是皮娅
That's Pia.
她怎么在这里
What's she doing here?
我还以为她没收到我的消息
I figured she never got my messages.
被害人的女儿吗
The victim's daughter?
你确定是她吗
Are you sure it's her?
这儿离迈阿密可远着呢
We're a long way from Miami.
长官 我很确定 这10年来那姑娘的长相
Sir, I'm positive. That girl's face has been
都刻进我的脑子里了
burned into my brain for ten years.
我等会儿去里面找你们
I'll meet you inside.
好
AII right.
你怎么在这里
What are you doing here?
洛杉矶警局派我们来护送完成这次引渡
LAPD needed an escort team for the extradition.
上级知道我跟韦尔杜戈的过去
And the higher- ups knew about my history with Verdugo.
所以我以为他们应该会派别人来
Which is why I figured they'd send someone else.
你还在迈阿密读书吗
You still studying in Miami?
之前是的
I was, yeah.
我不是来闹聊的
Mira, I am not here to make small talk.
我只想看着那混蛋的眼睛
I just want to look the bastard in the eye.
我也一样 皮娅
You and me both, Pia.
听着 我知道今天不太合适 但下次
Look, I know today is not the day, but the next time
你要是去了洛杉矶 记得联系我 好吗
you're in Los Angeles, give me a call, okay?
还是算了吧
I don't think so.
这就好了吗
That's everything?
现在我们去机场 等你们的飞机起飞
Now we go to airport. Once your plane is wheels up,
韦尔杜戈就正式交给美国了
Verdugo is officially in US. custody.
感觉正义终于到来了吗
Feel like justice is finally served?
那还是得等他被判无期吧
Once he's sentenced to life, maybe.
你们俩上跟着的那辆车
You two in the follow vehicle.
你跟我来
You're with me.
谁赶紧去检查一下那个包
Hey, somebody ought to check that bag!
有枪 找掩休
Gun! Coverl
别起来 帕维尔
Stay down, Powell
这他妈怎么回事
What the hell just happened?
韦尔杜戈跑了
Verdugo's gone.
他又跑了
He got away again.
醒醒 睁眼 看着我
Hey, hey, open your eyes, look at me.
看着我 睁眼
Look at me open your eyes.
你会没事的 没事的
You're gonna be okay. You're all right.
帕维尔 是他 蓝色连帽衫 12点钟方向
Powell, that's him. Blue hoodie, 12 o'clock
你去 这里交给我
Go! I got him.
稳住他
Keep him stable.
急救人员 赶紧找急救人员
POWELL: MediclIneed a medic!
给我下来
Heyl Get down
不不不 别跳
No, no, no. Don't do it.
他去哪儿了
Where'd he go?
还有所有大桥 通路和高速
OLVERA: And I also want checkpoints at every bridge,
还所有大桥 通路和高速
都设置关卡
road and highway.
如果韦尔杜戈计划先躲在这里
If Verdugo plans on hiding in the area
然后趁着夜色逃走
and slipping out under cover of night,
那就让我们给他来个惊喜
he's in for a surprise.
还干等什么呢 去啊
洪多和加布里埃尔还在
Are Hondo and Gabriel still talking
-和外面的警探问话吗  -是的
to detectives outside? Yes.
可以确定跳屋顶的那个
It appears our rooftop jumper was
的确是放炸弹的人
indeed who set the bomb.
我们在他手上发现了塑胶炸药残留
Semtex residue was found on his hands.
调查员们想要一次完整的汇报
The investigators want a full debrief.
听着 警长 我们知道你一定很忙
Look, Captain, we know you got your hands full,
所以如果今天有任何
so any assistance
我们可以帮忙的地方
we can provide today,
请你记得 洛杉矶警局愿意且随时可以提供帮助
know that the LAPD is ready and willing to provide it.
既然你们可以在墨西哥境内持有武器
Since you are permitted to carry firearms on Mexican soil
那我就此许可你们
I hereby deputize you to work in tandem
就再次逮捕韦尔杜戈一事
with the Mexican authorities
与墨西哥警方合作
for the sole purposes of Verdugo's recapture.
那人手上的B
The"B° on that man's hand.
韦尔杜戈也有个一样的
Verdugo has the same one.
那是黑帮的纹身吗
5, 485 Is that a Mafia tat? 65m O fp
B是Bestia的B 代表野兽
B"for Bestia. Beast.
"B"for Bestia. Beast.
是他们黑帮最为残忍的分支
It's their Mafia's most cutthroat branch.
他们和当地一些
They work with some of the region's
最为暴力的角色合作
most violent actors
人贩子 恐怖分子 这一类的
human traffickers, terrorists, you name it.
野兽的人只有一个兴趣 那就是钱
Bestias are interested in only one thing. Money° fpm
他们帮助韦尔杜戈逃跑不单纯是因为忠诚
They didn't just help Verdugo escape out of loyalty.
你看那辆摩托车
Look at that motorcycle there.
看到侧边的纹样了吗
See a pattern on the side?
看上去像是有某种贴纸
It seems like some sort of sticker was
被撕掉了 像是
peeled off like a 旦
-棋盘格  -那是他们当地
checkerboard pattern. That's the new emblem
足球俱乐部的新队徽
for their local football club. Soccer.
也就是说他是在这里买的这辆摩托车
Which means he bought the motorcycle in the area,
SUPERVISING PRODUCER
也就是说他是在这里买的这辆摩托车
而且是不久以前
not too long ago either.
但为什么要撕掉贴纸呢 混入本地不是更好吗
But why peel off the sticker? Wouldn't you want to blend in?
如果他经常离开这里
Not if he was regularly
往东边去 就不一样了
leaving the area, traveling east of here.
他们是敌对俱乐部的粉丝
They support a rival team. 65m O fp
那种贴纸司能会给你惹上麻烦
A sticker like that could get you into trouble.
赶紧查他到底是在哪儿买的摩托车
Let's find out where he got that motorcycle.
追捕开始
Let the manhunt begin.
你先进去
Hey. Go ahead inside.
我得去看看看一个人有没有事
I want to check on someone.
你们居然又让韦尔杜戈逃走了
I can't believe you let Verdugo get away again.
我花了那么多功夫才找到他
After all the work I put into tracking him down.
你花的功夫 什么意思
The work you put in? What do you mean?
等一下 皮娅
Wait a minute, Pia.
打给本地警局 告发他的匿名电话
Are you the one who made the anonymous call
是你打的吗
that tipped off the local police to him?
是啊
Yeah.
我真是太蠢了
How dumb am I?
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER
Trusting cops after everything I've been through.
都经历了这么多事了 我居然还相信警察
我 我不明白 你是怎么找到他的
II don't get it. How'd you find him?
我听到传言说 韦尔杜戈逃到了中美洲
I heard the rumors that Verdugo fled to Central America,
所以我就开始到处跑
so Istarted traveling.
你从迈阿密的学校退学了吗
You dropped out of school in Miami?
杀死我妈的男人还在逍遥法外
Sitting in class just seemed so ridiculous,
我觉得要我干坐在课堂上也太荒谬了
knowing the man who killed my mom was still out there.
我去了萨尔瓦多 危地马拉 这里
I've been to El Salvador, Guatemala, here.
开始用约会软件
Started using dating apps,
跟萨尔瓦多黑帮里底层的人约会
going on dates with low- level guys in Salvadoran gangs.
皮娅 这太危险了
Pia, that can be very dangerous
我总得做点什么 洪多
I had to do something, Hondo.
除了我没有别人在努力了
Nobody else was putting the work in.
你们显然是没有
You guys certainly weren't.
好吧 听着
Okay, look.
我知道你对警方和我的感受
I know you have your reasons for feeling
不是没有理由的
the way you do about police and me.
我不乖妞
And I don't blame you.
好吗 你小时候经历的悲剧
Okay? The tragedy you experienced as a child
那不是什么悲剧
It wasn't a tragedy.
悲剧是你无法改变的事情
A tragedy is something that just happens.
车祸 飓风
A car accident, a hurricane.
韦尔杜戈杀了我妈 是因为你说服了她
Verdugo killed my mom because you talked her
去指证他
into informing on him.
我妈妈的死是因为你
My mother's dead because of you.
事情没有这么简单 皮娅
There's more to it than that, Pia.
她被杀那天晚上
Night of the murder,
你跟我保证过 你会找到韦尔杜戈的
you promised me you'd find Verdugo.
但你没有
But you didn't.
是我找到了他
I'm the one who found him.
你把他弄丢了
You lost him.
两次了
Twice now.
我理解你的感受
I understand how you feel.
但你记住
But know this- -
我一定不会让这种事再发生了
I am determined to not let this happen again.
但听着 如果你知道
But, look, if you know anything else
韦尔杜戈可能在哪里
about where Verdugo might be
我不知道
I don't.
但就算我知道
But even if I did,
又为什么要告诉你呢
why would I ever tell you?
那个摔死的男人身份确定了
The man who fell to his death was ID'd
他叫马里奥·占铁雷斯一
as Mario Gutierrez.
这是隔壁楼监控录像拍到的
This is from the neighboring building's surveillance cam,
就在公寓对面
across the street from the apartment.
知道他这两个兄弟是谁了吗
Any clue who his buddies are?
中间的这个男人应该是
The man in the middle is thought to be
韦尔杜戈最亲密的同伙之一
one of Verdugo's closest associates.
那很有可能
Then there's a good chance
韦尔杜戈就躲在那里
that's where Verdugo is holed up.
那辆撕掉贴纸的摩托车
That bike with the peeled- off sticker?
你是对的 警长
You were right, Capitan.
它是上周城东一家
It was purchased just last week
废品回收场卖出去的
from a salvage yard east of town.
据说那里的所有人和黑帮有关系
The owner is rumored to have gang affiliations.
野兽帮
Las Bestias.
你们过去 看看能有什么发现
Get there. See what you can find.
我们可能查到了韦尔杜戈一个左膀右臂的所在地
We may have a location on one of Verdugo's top deputies.
我去整合队伍里其他人
I'll round up the rest of the team.
-我想跟他一起去 指挥官  -这里不是我的地盘
I'd like to go with him, Commander. Not mi casa.
由不得我决定
Not my call
走吧 我们去抓韦尔杜戈
Come on. Time to bring Verdugo in.
所以你对美国的一切了解
So everything you know about America,
都来源于萨克拉门托  -还有比这更好的学习之处吗
you learned in Sacramento. What better place to learn?
那是最美的城市
It is the most beautiful city.
它确实有自己的魅力
I mean, it has its charms,
但我不觉得它有那么好
but I'm not sure that's how I would describe it.
我感觉你从来没有在萨克拉门托河上
You sound like a woman who's never taken a sunset cruise
体验过落日游轮
down the Sacramento River.
被你说中了
Guilty as charged.
所以 你是什么时候
So, when exactly did you participate
参与这次警方交流项目的
in this police exchange program?
三年前
Three years ago.
当时我刚刚跟我老婆离婚
My wife and I had just gotten divorced,
看到了报名表 想着我得离开这里
I saw the sign- up sheet, and decided I had to get away.
萨克拉门托是个很适合疗愈的地方
Sacramento was a good place to heal.
-你们结婚多久  -11年
How long were you two married? 11 years.
我们是青梅竹马
We were childhood sweethearts.
她是我的初恋
My first love.
从来没想过自己能放下这段感情
Never thought I'd get over it.
相信我 我懂
Trust me. I know the feeling
我前夫和我是高中时候的情侣
My ex- husband and I were high school sweethearts.
一样的
Same story.
听着 在我们进去之前 你要知道
Listen, before we go in, you should know that people
这里的人出了名的是 不爱多说话
in this town aren't known for being. talkative.
我们进去之后 我来和店主对话
When we get inside, I'll speak to the owner.
你到处看看有没有线索
You take a look around for anything of interest.
你们是警察
我是包蒂斯塔警官 这位是我的同事
你一个人吗
是啊 怎么了
我们有几个问题要问你
怎么样了 洪多
What up, Hondo?
我们在那个跳楼的人公寓里没搜出什么东西
Our search for the jumper's apartment turned up empty.
没有发现韦尔杜戈或者他的团伙
No sign of Verdugo or his crew.
你那边怎么样了
How's it going over there?
加布里埃尔正在
Gabriel's talking
询问店主
to the owner now.
我也看不出来有没有进展
Can't tell if he's getting anywhere.
我正在店外面看看
I'm taking a look out back now.
好 有消息及时通知我
All right. Keep me posted. MX 832- 40
没问题
You got it.
朋友
Amigo,
你会说英语吗
you speak English?
-一点吧  -你住在这附近吗
Maybe. You live around here?
你知道那栋楼的28公寓里
Do you have any idea who lives
住的是谁吗
in Apartment 2B in that building?
我不知道你是哪里来的
I don't know where you're from,
但在这里 想要东西 你得付钱
but here, if you want something, you pay.
那你最好是有真材实料 兄弟
Oh, this better be real good, my man.
上周来的姑娘付了五倍的钱
Girl who came last week paid five times this much.
什么姑娘
What girl?
我又不认识
I don't know.
但她超正点的
She was hot, though.
长得像A妹
Looked like Ariana Grande.
她也问起了住在2B的男人们
She also asked about the men in 2B.
她该不会是叫皮娅吧
Her name Pia by any chance?
我也问了 她说我还太年轻
I asked. Said I was too young.
不肯给我电话号码
Wouldn't give me her number.
她说如果我想到了别的
Said I could find her at Cafe Terraza
可以去特拉萨咖啡馆找她
if I thought of anything more.
那祝你下次好运了 花花公子
Yeah, well, better luck next time, playboy.
不用找零了
Keep the change.
原地别动
Stop right there.
转过来 举起手来
Turn around, put your hands up.
趴下别动
Get your ass down.
韦尔杜戈躲在哪里
Where's Verdugo hiding, huh?
看来我错过了精彩部分
Looks like I missed the fun part.
是啊
: Yeah.
下一个你来
Get the next one.
起来
Get up
街上到处都是警察 费尔南多
The streets are flooded with police, Fernando.
你现在想要减刑 唯一的办法就是
Your only hope at a reduced sentence is
在我们找到韦尔杜戈之前
to tell us where Verdugo's hiding
告诉我们他躲在哪里
before we find him.
因为她在 我们就要说英语吗
她到底为什么在这
你心里清楚美国人为什么过来
You know exactly why the Americans are here.
韦尔杜戈在哪里
Where's Verdugo?
费尔南多的手机 你看看
Fernando's phone. Check it out.
准备告诉我们这是谁吗
Want to tell us who she is?
我跟她不熟
I barely know her. Hmm.
你这几十张照片看着倒是挺熟的
There's two dozen photos in here that say otherwise.
警长说她是一个叫Caricero的男人的
Capitan says she's the 16- year- old daughter
16岁的女儿
of a man called Carnicero.
Carnicero是什么意思
What does Carnicero mean?
屠夫
Butcher. Huh.
他的小女朋友的爸 是德尔加多屠夫
His little girlfriend's dad is"the Butcher of Delgado. "
居然敢搞上
Messing around with the daughter
人称屠夫的人的女儿
of a guy called "the Butcher. "
我真是很好奇 一个臭名昭著的黑帮屠夫
I wonder what a notorious Mafia butcher would do if he saw
看到这种照片 会做什么
a picture like this.
韦尔杜戈安排了一场高额交易
Verdugo had a high- stakes deal lined up.
本来是要大赚一笔的
Supposed to make him a fortune.
但是在交易之前 他就被抓了
But he got arrested before the big deal went down.
韦尔杜戈在卖什么
What was Verdugo selling?
-毒品吗  -我不知道
Drugs? No se.
我只知道是一个叫大胡子的男人安排的交易
All I know is that a man called El Barbon set up the deal.
他有胡子 长头发
He has beard, long hair.
这个大胡子有真名吗
Does El Barbon have a real name?
叫埃米尔
Emil something.
姓波蒂略  还是波利托 反正波打头的
Portillo, Polito, something with"P. "
埃米尔负责给韦尔杜戈和买家牵线
Emil is brokering the deal between Verdugo and the buyer.
你们找到埃米尔 就离韦尔杜戈不远了
You find Emil, Verdugo won't be far.
他没拿到钱是不会离开这里的
He won't leave town until he gets that money.
皮娅
Pia.
-我们能聊聊吗  -聊什么
Can we talk for a second? About what?
我感觉你对韦尔杜戈下落的了解
I got a feeling that you know more
还没有完全告诉我们
about Verdugo's whereabouts than you're letting on.
皮娅 我们搜查了城另一边的一所公寓
Pia, we raided an apartment across town.
附近的一个男孩说
A neighborhood boy said that you
你已经去过那儿 拍过照了
had already been there taking pictures.
小混蛋
Little punk
拜托 告诉我
Come on, talk to me.
你的消息源那边有什么好线索吗
Are you finding any good leads from the sources you're working?
没有
No.
我订了明早飞回迈阿密的机票
I'm booking a flight back home to Miami tomorrow morning.
或许我可以找份工作 重新去读书
Maybe I can get a job, reenroll in school.
今天早上的事情
What happened this morning
我实在承受不来
was all too much.
而且我也快没钱了
And I'm running out of money.
我不能再花10年
I can't spend another ten years
沉浸在这些阴暗的想法里
consumed with such dark thoughts.
我妈妈肯定也不希望我这样
It's not what my mother would have wanted for me.
这是肯定的
You're definitely right about that.
听着 这10年来你是离找到韦尔杜戈
Listen, you came closer than anyone has in a decade
最近的一个人了
to finding Verdugo.
那我为什么感觉这么失败
Then why do I feel like such a failure?
因为你累了 皮娅
Because you're tired, Pia.
回佛罗里达 过你自己的生活
Go back to Florida, go back to your life.
我会尽自己所能
I will do everything I can
确保他不会再逃跑的
to make sure he doesn't get away again.
别保证了
No promises.
我不保证 但我会努力的
No promises, but I will try
你要知道 你妈妈肯定很为你骄傲
Your mother would be really proud of you, you know.
照顾好自己
You take care of yourself.
听好了
HICKS: Hey, listen to this.
今早警局外的爆炸物残留
The explosive found outside the station this morning?
鉴证科在迫击炮弹壳上发现了一个序列号
Forensics lab found a serial number on the mortar shell.
弹壳 所以怎么 那个被引爆的炸弹
"Shell. "So, what, the bomb that was detonated
是军用装备吗
was a military armament?
上个月在危地马拉边境
Apparently an artillery truck was hijacked
有一辆炮兵卡车遭劫
last month near the Guatemalan border.
他们抢走了火箭弹 迫击炮弹
The thieves got away with RPGs, mortars,
还有一个温压弹
and a thermobaric vacuum bomb.
总价值两百万美元
Altogether worth $2 million.
要是在人口密集的地方
A thermobaric vacuum bomb
引爆温压弹 那
detonated in a populated area would.
会杀死上千人 是的
It could kill thousands, yes.
那现在我们是怀疑这次劫案背后是韦尔杜戈吗
We think Verdugo was behind the hijacking?
不 我们确定了
No, we know it.
在抢劫过程中死掉的劫匪
The hijacker killed during the robbery
叫利奥·韦尔杜戈
is named Leo Verdugo.
他是韦尔杜戈的表亲
It's one of Verdugo's cousins.
韦尔杜戈这么迫切想要完成交易
And the reason why Verdugo was so hot to make the deal,
就是因为交易的是遭窃的武器
it's the stolen weapons.
最新消息你听说了吗
Did you hear the latest?
我刚在跟她说
I was just filling her in.
感觉是不能落入
Sounds like weapons you don't want
坏人手中的武器
falling into the wrong hands.
韦尔杜戈被抓的时候肯定是
OLVERA: Verdugo must have been about to sell them
马上要卖了
when he got arrested.
现在他逃脱了
Now that he's free,
我们认为他会计划在24小时内
we think he's going to plan to make the deal
完成这笔交易
within the next 24 hours.
-你怎么能确定  -因为这个男人
How can you be so sure? Because this man here?
他昨天从危地马拉飞过来了
He flew in from Guatemala yesterday.
埃米尔·佩拉尔塔
Emil Peralta.
那个摩托车手确认了他就是大胡子
Our biker ID'd him as El Barbon.
就是他在给韦尔杜戈
The one brokering the deal
和那个买家牵线搭桥
between Verdugo and whoever's buying.
他的据点在危地马拉 但是他每几个月
He's based in Guatemala but travels to Mexico City
就要来墨西哥城 给本地的酒吧还有餐厅
every few months. Sells black market liquor
卖黑市酒
to local bars and restaurants in the area.
他很低调
Keeps a very low profile.
这些是传言中他卖货的地区
These are the spots he's rumored to sell his products.
也是最经常出现的地方
And most likely frequents.
我们分成两两一组 进行监控
Let's split up into pairs and do stakeouts.
十
好
All right.
-通知大家  -明白
Tell the troops Yes ma'am.
这里没有发现埃米尔
No sign of Emil here.
这一边也没有发现
No luck on this side of town either.
目前为止毫无进展
Coming up empty so far.
收到
POWELL: Roger.
我知道这一般是早餐
I know it's breakfast food,
但公园里也就能买到这些了
but it's the best I can do in the park
谢了 我快饿死了
Thanks. I'm starving.
这不如我奶奶做的
It's not as good as my abuela's,
但至少你可以尝尝
but at least you get to try them.
我的天 这好像油炸饼
Oh, my, it's like a funnel cake,
但要好吃一千倍
only a thousand times better.
你喜欢就好
I'm glad you like it.
我还喜欢这里的很多地方
There's a lot of things I like about this place.
或许这次追捕再多花上几天
You know, maybe it wouldn't be the worst thing
可能也不坏
if this manhunt took a few more days.
是他 是埃米尔
That's him. That's Emil.
来吧 这边
Come on, this way.
我看到他往西走了 在危地马拉共和国
I spot him headed west, Republica de Guatemala.
他发现我们了
He spotted us.
让开 让开
Move, move.
我们跟丢了
We lost him.
你和奥尔维拉警长聊过了吗
You speak to Captain Olvera?
刚挂电话
Just hung up.
这一晚上也没有埃米尔的线索
There were no overnight leads on Emil.
他完全可能已经回危地马拉了
He's probably already back in Guatemala City, for all we know.
现在我们惊动了韦尔杜戈的中间人
HICKS: Now that we spooked Verdugo's middleman,
你觉得他还会继续这次武器交易吗
you think he still plans on carrying out this weapons deal?
韦尔杜戈和一大笔收入之间
There's one meeting standing between
只差了一次会面
Verdugo and a huge payday.
而且如果买家愿意付钱
And if his buyers are paying,
那现在就没有什么能拦住韦尔杜戈
nothing's stopping Verdugo now.
我们得查出这交易到底在哪儿进行
We need to find out where the hell this deal's going down.
要是在洛杉矶 我们就能找线人做做工作
If this were LA we'd be able to work some CI
说不定就能带我们找到韦尔杜戈团伙里的人
who might have a lead to someone in Verdugo's crew.
长官 我得去打个电话
Sir, I'm gonna make a quick call.
你等一下
Hang tight.
应该不用我提醒你
I hope I don't have to remind you
我们还在执行公务吧
that we're here in a professional capacity.
加布里埃尔只是人好
Gabriel was just nice enough
今早给我带了个羊角面包来
to bring me a croissant this morning. Oh,
行吧 不错
well, yeah. That's nice.
怎么了 你不相信我吗
What? You don't believe me?
不 只是
No, it's, uh
听着 说实话 这都不关我事
Look, frankly, it's none of my business.
你说得对
You're right.
我搭加布里埃尔的车去
I'm gonna catch a ride in with Gabriel.
那就警局见了 指挥官
So I'll just see you at the station, Commander.
长官
HONDO: Sir.
皮娅可能差一点
Pia might've been close
就能搞到韦尔杜戈交易地点的小道消息了
to getting a tip on where Verdugo's deal is happening.
她说一小时后可以在青年旅舍见
She said she'd meet us at her hostel in an hour,
在她去机场之前
before she leaves for the airport.
好 我们走
AII right...let's go.
抱歉 长官 但你为什么会操心
Sorry, sir, but what made you feel like Powell's love life
帕维尔的感情生活呢
was any of your concern?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说 帕维尔总是让我想起莫莉
No, I mean, Powell's always reminded me of Molly.
很固执 有能力 但
You know, headstrong, so capable but
本质是个浪漫主义者
a romantic at heart.
我想我就是
I guess I
不想看到她陷入一段感情
don't want to see her have a fling
最后受伤吧
and end up getting hurt.
我大概欠她一个道歉
Probably owe Powell an apology.
我想也是
I'd say so.
皮娅现在应该已经过来了才对
Pia should've been here by now.
有什么可以帮到你们吗
Can I help you?
有
HICKS: Yes, you can.
这个女孩是住在这儿的吗
Is this girl staying here?
-对  -你今天见过她吗
Yeah. Did you see her today?
我昨晚看到她出去 但再也没回来
I saw her leave last night, but she never came back.
她住哪间房
What room was she staying in?
212 就在那边
212. Just down there.
你这儿有监控吗
Do you have security cameras?
不全是有用的
Not all of them are working,
但我可以给你看看现有的
but I can show you what we have.
那就太好了
That'll be fantastic.
你能不能
Could you, uh
-调出昨天的  -可以
cue it up to yesterday? Yeah.
能稍微倒一点吗
Can you just rewind just a little bit back?
就这儿 停一下
R- Right there, stop.
就是她 是皮娅
That's her. That's Pia.
那是昨天晚上的
That's from yesterday evening.
午夜之后不久
Right after midnight.
指挥官
HONDO: Commander.
她的东西都还在房间里
All her stuff's still in the room.
都没收拾
None of it's packed.
看上去她昨晚是
Well, it seems like she made it
安全回来这里的
back here safely last night.
你知道这家伙是谁吗
HONDO: Do you have any idea who that guy is?
我还真知道
Yeah, actually.
大家都叫他Boki
People call him Boki.
他是个desgraciado
He's a, a desgraciado
就是你们说的变态
How you say"creep. "
他在特皮托 住在自己车里
He lives in his van in Tepito.
为了钱他什么都干
He'll do anything for a dollar.
就这儿 暂停一下
Stop the video right there for me.
放大
Zoom in.
-指挥官 你看 他有枪  -是啊
Commander, look, he's got a gun. HICKS: Yeah.
如果皮娅被绑架了
If Pia was abducted,
那我们已经没多少时间了
we're already working on borrowed time.
谢谢你
Hey, thank you.
你就是Boki吗
Is your name Boki?
干嘛 老头
What you want, old man?
我是条子
I'm a cop.
就是警察
Police officer.
慢点 慢点
Slow down, slow down.
皮娅在哪里
Where's Pia?
-谁  -住青旅的那个美国女孩
Who? The American girl in the youth hostel.
我们知道你昨晚跟踪她到了那里
We know you followed her in there last night.
松手 放开我
Get off me. Let me go.
是谁让你跟踪她的 她人在哪里
HICKS: Who put you up to this? Where is she?
是有人付钱给你 让你去伤害她吗
Did somebody pay you to hurt her?
伤害她 我没伤害任何人
Hurt her? I did not hurt no one.
她要买枪 所以我就卖给她一把手枪
She wanted to buy a gun, so I sold her a pistol.
点380囗径的
A little 380.
如果皮娅买了枪
Well, if Pia bought a gun,
那她肯定知道韦尔杜戈在哪里
she knows where Verdugo is.
她自己去结果他了
She went to take care of him herself.
你给我听好了
You listen to me.
那姑娘现在处境很危险
That girl is in serious danger.
你知道她要去哪儿吗
Do you have any idea where she was going?
我没问
I didn't ask.
我走的时候
When I was leaving,
听到她叫了今早的出租车
I heard her order a taxi for this morning.
说了什么fabrica 521
Mentioned some fabrica 521.
那是什么
What is that?
我他妈怎么知道
How the hell am I supposed to know?
洪多 你找到这个Boki了吗
Hondo. You find this Boki guy?
是 帕维尔 我们找到他了
HONDO: Yeah, Powell, we got him.
但他没有绑架皮娅
But he did not abduct Pia.
而是卖给她一把枪
He sold her a gun.
听着 她和黑帮里底层的人有联系
Look, she's got low level contacts in the Mafia.
肯定是有人告诉了她
One of them must've tipped her off
韦尔杜戈的交易在哪里进行
to wherever Verdugo's deal is going down.
个叫fabrica521的地方
Some place called fabrica 521.
fabrica 521是什么意思
What does fabrica 521 mean?
521工厂
Factory 521.
韦尔杜戈肯定是要在
Verdugo must be carrying out his deal
旧工业区进行交易
in the old industrial district.
去工业区汇合
Meet us in the industrial district.
我给你发定位
Il drop you a pin.
去车那儿等着
听我命令 把武器拿过来
一定要等我命令
这里就是521工厂
OLVERA: This is fabrica 521.
已废弃的运输设施
Defunct shipping facility.
我们有理由相信韦尔杜戈
We have reason to believe Verdugo intends
准备尽快完成他的军火交易
to carry out his arms deal imminently.
等我们过去之后 你们俩
Once we're there, you two take
去大楼的最西端
the westernmost part of the building.
没时间浪费了 我们走
No time to waste. Go!
听着像点380口径的枪声吗
That sound like a 380 to you?
是皮娅
It's Pia.
有埋伏
找掩体
Take cover!
皮娅 你在哪里
Pia! Where are you?
有人告诉我 你一直在我的人周围打探
A little birdie told me you've been
试图把我找出来
sniffing around my men, trying to find me.
现在我来了
Well, here I am!
你听到那尖叫了吗
Did you hear that scream?
是里面传出来的
Came from inside.
无处可逃了吧
VERDUGO: Nowhere to run, huh?
别这么做
Don't do this.
站着别动 韦尔杜戈
Stop right there, Verdugo!
我建议你们还是别过来了
Would not come any closer if I were you!
他是要把她吊起来
He's gonna hang her from the rafters,
给自己争取时间逃跑
try to buy himself time to escape.
别这么做 放她走
Don't do it, man! Let her go!
警长
Captain.
我们在最西端大楼的一楼
We're on the main floor of the westernmost building.
正在面对人质劫持
We have a hostage situation.
-放开我  -闭嘴
PIA: Let me go. VERDUGO: Shut up!
10年前 你救了她
Ten years ago, you save her.
恐怕这次你做不到了
I'm afraid it won't happen again.
我打不到他
I can't get a clean shot off.
我也是
Yeah, neither can I
你不需要伤害她
HONDO: You don't need to hurt the girl.
我们都可以活着离开这里
We can all walk out of here.
拜托 住手吧
sPlease stop
放开她
Let her go.
你放了她 我们就让你离开
You release her, we will let you run out of here.
我们会告诉其他人 我们没找到你
We'll tell the others that we couldn't find you.
我小时候我叔叔就教过我
My uncles taught me when I was young
永远不要相信条子
never to trust a cop
听着 我不能保证
Look, I can't guarantee what'll happen
你出去之后会怎么样
once you re out there,
但我告诉你
but I am telling you,
我们会让你离开 不对你开枪
we will let you leave without firing a shot at you.
这样你至少有个机会
At least you'll get a chance.
拜托 你说呢
Come on, man. What do you say?
别伤害她 慢慢放开她就行
Don't hurt her. Just let her go nice and easy.
洪多
Hondo.
指挥官 打绳子
Commander, rope!
我来了
I got you.
我来了 有我呢 好了
I got you, I got you. All right.
把这个拿下来 好了
Get this off. All right,
都结束了 皮娅
it's all over now, Pia.
好吗 我们送你去医院
Okay? We'll get you tended to.
韦尔杜戈团伙里有活下来的吗
HICKS: Anyone in Verdugo's crew survive?
很不幸 就一个
OLIVERA: Just one, unfortunately.
但他也不一定能挺过来
Not sure if he'll make it, though.
-可能挺过来也会有后遗症  -是啊
Or if he'll be the same if he does. Yeah.
看来你们得空手
Appears you'll be heading back to Los Angeles
回洛杉矶了
without your prisoner.
这样我们就能在飞机上睡会儿了
Oh, it should make it easier for us to catch some sleep
还是会轻松一点的
on the plane.
听着 我也经历过 我知道行动结束
Look, I know from experience that when the action's over
领导的工作才刚刚开始
the boss's job is just beginning.
我相信你有很多文书工作要做 警长
I'm sure you got a lot of paperwork to get to, Captain,
所以 我就不打扰你了
sO. I'll let you get to it.
怎么了 你在想什么
What is it? What's on your mind?
韦尔杜戈
Verdugo.
我们没在他身上找到手机
We didn't find a cell phone on him.
他肯定是在混乱之中在这儿掉了手机
HICKS: I'm sure he dropped it somewhere around here in the chaos.
或许吧
Maybe.
我们还没找到
We haven't found it yet.
怎么了
HICKS: What is it?
我们在仓库背后找到了一堆武器
We found a stockpile of weapons behind the warehouse.
火箭弹 迫击炮弹
RPGs, mortars.
所以我们赶在韦尔杜戈的交易完成之前赶到了
So we got here before Verdugo's deal went down.
不一定 我们可能已经来晚了
Not necessarily. We might have gotten here too late.
那个温压弹
The thermobaric vacuum bomb- -
不见了 根本找不到
it's gone, there's no sign of it.
韦尔杜戈可能已经把它卖了
GABRIEL: Verdugo may have already sold it.
如果是真的 那这就是最糟糕的情况了
If that's true, that's the worst news possible.
那种炸弹 如果落在坏人手里
A bomb like that could cause unimaginable destruction
可能会造成无法想象的破坏
in the wrong hands.
不管韦尔杜戈把那炸弹卖给谁了
Whoever Verdugo sold that bomb to
我们都得尽快把他找出来
we need to find him fast.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我得去联系上级
I need to call my bosses,
警告各个联邦机构
alert the federal agencies. Mm- hmm.
她的事儿还多着呢
She's got a long night ahead of her.
我想你人概也得走了吧
I imagine you probably got to get going, too,
包蒂斯塔警官
Officer Bautista.
我还真不用 他们让我下班了
No, actually. They took me off the clock.
预算削减
Budget cuts.
不给我们加班费了
Stopped giving us overtime.
我在想 如果你没有什么安排的话
I was wondering, if you didn't have any plans.
我很乐意
I'd love to.
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
是好几个道歉
A few of them, actually.
过去几天 我对你
I haven't been very nice to you
态度不太好
the last couple days.
PO LICIA
Pia.
皮娅
过去几年 做特警队队长的经历
Being a SWAT team leader these last couple years
教会了我很多关于责任的事情
has taught me a lot about responsibility.
而且现在我做爸爸了
And now I'm a parent.
我不该在无法百分百确定自己可以遵守的情况下
I never should've made a promise
就做出承诺
that I wasn't 100%sure I could keep.
我真的很抱歉 因为我知道 我让你有多失望
And I have been so sorry because I know how much I let you down.
我觉得这其实帮到了我
I think it helped me, actually.
我一直在试图说服自己 我妈妈的事
Trying to convince myself there was someone else to blame
是可以怪在别人头上的
for what happened to my mom.
但现实是
When in reality,
她会死是因为我
she died because of me.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
10年前
Ten years ago,
你送我们去安全屋的时候
when you dropped us off at the safe house,
告诉我们 只能带几身衣服
you told us that we could only bring a few changes of clothes.
不能带电子用品 不能带手机
No electronics, no phones.
但那天我骗了你
But I lied to you that day.
我趁着你没注意的时候
I snuck my cell phone into my bag
把手机塞包里了
when you weren't looking.
韦尔杜戈大概就是这样找到我们的
That's probably how Verdugo found me and my mom.
皮娅 别这样
Pia, don't do that.
不要自责
Don't blame yourself.
当时你只是个孩子
You were just a child.
你知道你妈妈为什么反过来指证韦尔杜戈了吗
Do you have any idea why your mother turned on Verdugo?
在她发现韦尔杜戈的犯罪活动
When she discovered the depth
有那么恐怖的时候 她就来找我们了
of Verdugo's criminal activity, she came to us.
她不希望有其他人受伤
She didn't want anyone to get hurt.
你妈妈是下定决心 要扳倒韦尔杜戈的
Your mom was determined to take Verdugo down.
就像你一样
Just like you were.
真的吗
Really?
不骗你
God's honest truth.
她只希望能让你远离他
AlI she wanted was to keep you away from him.
现在我终于做到了
Now I finally am.
你自由了
You're free.
你看着好美
You look amazing.
你也不错啊 警官
Not so bad yourself, Officer.
-房间不错啊  -谢谢
Nice digs. Thanks.
我们的预约被推迟了一个小时
Our reservation was pushed back an hour,
所以我们可以消磨一些时间
so we have some time to kill.
甜甜圈
Doughnuts.
你是真喜欢烘培食品啊
You're really all about the baked goods, huh?
我不是抱怨啊
Not that I'm complaining.
是我奶奶打来的
Ah, it's my abuelita.
我能接一下吗
Do you mind?
行啊 去吧
Sure, go ahead.
嗨 对 奶奶
Alo. Si, abuela?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
是你拿走了炸弹
You took the bomb.
嗨 要小酌一杯吗
Hey. You interested in a nightcap?
不了 指挥官
HONDO: I don t think so, Commander.
我准备睡了
I'm hitting the rack.
你问问帕维尔 指不定她愿意
Give Powell a ring, maybe she's up for it.
我觉得她现在可能不是太想见我
Yeah, I doubt I'm her favorite person right now.
而且我听到她今晚约了加布里埃尔
Plus, I heard her making plans with Gabriel tonight.
帕维尔是住407的对吧
HICKS: Powell's in 407, right?
我记得是 怎么了 让我猜猜
HONDO: Yeah, I think so. Why? Oh, let me guess.
你还没来得及跟她道歉
You didn't get a chance to apologize to her yet,
又觉得自己该道歉
and you feel like you should.
你真是个聪明鬼
Ah, you think you're so smart.
帕维尔肯定会感谢你的
Hey, I'm sure Powell would appreciate it.
她应该还在
She's probably still around.
她好像电视机还开着
I think she's got the TV on or something.
我们可以飞机上再聊
Ah, we can talk on the plane.
好 晚安 指挥官
AlI right. Good night, Commander.
好 你好好休息
Yeah. Get some rest.